CURRICULUM VITAE





Professional Profile

I'm professional with international experience with focus on technological solution for the energy sector. In the beginning years of my career, I worked as an engineer developing integrated software solutions, Scada systems (HMI) on E3 Elipse platform, automation, meter components, embedded systems, integrations with smart metering devices (Siemens, Schneider (ION), EIG and Itron), industrial net protocols (Modbus), systems based of Microsoft .Net C#, language C e C++. Oracle for data store (PL/SQL). Scrum methodology for management and development.

I'm actually part of the projects area, fixing and setting requirements with clients, "Product Owner" (Scrum), technical specification and project scope, institutional and product corporative presentations, Demos implementation, test system environment, business negotiation Skills, commercial support, and provide economics and technical proposal documents, providing corporative training for IT and operational areas (End-Users), supervision and control projects with software tools.

Formal Education

Master (Current)

Software and hardware for Embedded Systems, Post-graduate Electric Engineering program. University "Federal do Estado de Santa Catarina" (UFSC) Florianopolis, Brazil

Electronic Engineering (10 semesters)

University "Escuela Colombiana de Ingeniería Julio Garavito" Bogotá, Colombia

Others:

2013	E3 Elipse Software Certify
2013	Courses Microsoft Project tool. (ASOCIEC Institute)
2012	Portuguese language Certify (proficiency)
2011	Course Microsoft .NET Framework 4, Visual Studio 2012.

Job Experience

2015-now **PrimeStone**

Area: Product.

Description: Consultant, business analyses, technical specifications, RoadMap,

software engineering, interfaces with clients.

Website: http://primestone.info/

2013 - 2015 **Way2 Technology**

Area: Projects and Operations.

Description: "Product Owner", commercial support (Pipeline), business analyses, trainer, delivering corporative proposal documents (technical and economics

descriptions) in Latin- America. Website: http://way2.com.br

2011 - 2012 Way2 Technology

Area: Development

Description: Development software solutions for the power energy sector, MDM and MDC systems based on Elipse E3 Software, .Net C# Microsoft and Oracle data base. Developer of Web interfaces, HMI, process automation, solutions integration and technical support for system and energy customers (Example: Codensa, Tractebel, Elektro, Enertolima etc).

Website: http://way2.com.br

2010 Montajes JM,

Area: Pacific Rubiales Energy, Colombia.

Description: Data monitoring, database, making Excel reports and support for logistic

areas of the oil company. Website: http://way2.com.br

2007 Ministry of Communication

Area: "Computadores para Educar" Program, Cauca, Colombia

Description: Engineer program delegate, project management, acceptance and validation the technical requirement for the infrastructure provided for a third party, in the execution for one state in the Colombian Government.

Website: www.computadoresparaeducar.gov.co

Software Skills

MS Microsoft (Project), Oracle PLSQL, Visual Studio, Mathlab, Cadence, Altera, PICs, Linux, VHDL, Redmine, OpenProject

Language Skills

Spanish: Native language.

English: Advance Portuguese: Fluent

Relative Information

Newspaper: http://diariocatarinense.clicrbs.com.br/sc/economia/noticia/2012/02/sc-

importa-profissionais-qualificados-3660666.html

Ex - AIESEC member: http://aiesec.org/about-aiesec/mission/

References

College: Victoria Donado. Business Manager at PrimeStone. +57 1-3563500
College: Hugo Kubo. Corporative Ex-change Manager at Aiesec. +55 48-99035857
College: Rodolpho Moura. Operation Manager at Stefanini. +55 51-83112126
College: Felipe Marques. Project Manager at Radix. +55 41-99266395
Coordinator: Djones lettin. Phd Computer Enginnering, UFSC. +55 48-96638307
Friend: Deocar Zimmerman. Account Manager, Banco Caixa. +55 47-91025299

Personal Information

Address: Lauro Linhares 1830, Apto 102. Florianopolis, SC.

Passport: AP980417 Date of birth: 15/12/1981

Email: jde 919@hotmail.com and david.pulido10@terra.com

Skype: jde919

Phone number: +55 (48) 99508022 // +573002164476

Other: (48) 96386980

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/pub/julian-espinosa-pulido/42/796/761

25.07.2015